<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="ENG_DF_000183_20150408_F0000009B">
<headline>
Technically A Clinton Clinton Ticket Would Be Legal.
</headline>
<post id="p1" author="TheMastersNemesis" datetime="2015-04-08T11:58:00">
Interestingly the idea came up on Chicago progressive talk radio. Apparently the law says Clinton could not be "elected" to t third term. Theoretically Bill Clinton could be run for VP. And if something happened to Hillary he could become president. And that would be legal.

Boy would such a ticket have the GOP and RW going completely insane. LOL
</post>
<post id="p2" author="dsc" datetime="2015-04-08T12:00:00">
1. It would cost us NY electorial votes

so that is a non starter.
</post>
<post id="p3" author="cali" datetime="2015-04-08T12:01:00">
2. I don't see how that's true.  The 12th Amendment states that in order to eligible

for the VP you have to be eligible for the Presidency.
</post>
<post id="p4" author="Action_Patrol" datetime="2015-04-08T12:04:00">
4. Beat me to it.
</post>
<post id="p5" author="hughee99" datetime="2015-04-08T12:06:00">
5. I'm pretty sure they're required to be from different states as well,

and both the Clinton's officially reside in NY.
</post>
<post id="p6" author="Adrahil" datetime="2015-04-08T12:08:00">
9. Quick check of the Constitution reveals no such requirement. n/t
</post>
<post id="p7" author="hughee99" datetime="2015-04-08T12:12:00">
13. Check the 12th Amendment.  This was brought up when Bush and Cheney were both "from" Texas.

The Electors shall meet in their respective states, and vote by ballot for President and Vice-President, one of whom, at least, shall not be an inhabitant of the same state with themselves; they shall name in their ballots the person voted for as President, and in distinct ballots the person voted for as Vice-President, and they shall make distinct lists of all persons voted for as President, and all persons voted for as Vice-President and of the number of votes for each, which lists they shall sign and certify, and transmit sealed to the seat of the government of the United States, directed to the President of the Senate.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twelfth_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution
</post>
<post id="p8" author="msanthrope" datetime="2015-04-08T12:14:00">
16. It applies to electors, not candidates.....

Snopes has a pretty good explanation.....

http://www.snopes.com/history/american/vicepresident.asp
</post>
<post id="p9" author="hughee99" datetime="2015-04-08T13:08:00">
30. Yes and no.

It means that the electoral votes from NY couldn't go to both Clintons. Assuming the electors of NY vote for Hillary, they COULDN'T vote for Bill for the VP. New York has 31 electoral votes, and if Clinton's margin of Victory is LESS than 31, then you could have president Clinton with a Republican vice president (having gotten the most votes for VP).

You're correct in that it's not specifically barred, and if the Clintons were both from Wyoming, it wouldn't be a big issue, but with 31 elector votes at stake (and for a host of other reasons), it's not going to happen.
</post>
<post id="p10" author="JonLP24" datetime="2015-04-08T15:13:00">
36. He could simply change his home state something else

How hard could it be for him to have Arkansas like Cheney changed from Texas to Wyoming. I doubt it will happen but doubt it is much of a roadblock.
</post>
<post id="p11" author="hughee99" datetime="2015-04-08T19:12:00">
45. Is it worth it, though?

I'll bet the last thing Hillary wants is her husband as VP. Not to mention the field day the press would have with a married couple not even "living the the same state".
</post>
<post id="p12" author="JonLP24" datetime="2015-04-08T19:23:00">
47. I don't think it will happen in reality

just don't think the changing the home states issue will be the reason why they don't. Like you said it would be controversial considering he did serve 2 terms &amp; things like what the would press would say, etc
</post>
<post id="p13" author="msanthrope" datetime="2015-04-08T12:13:00">
14. Correct.  nt
</post>
<post id="p14" author="Adrahil" datetime="2015-04-08T12:07:00">
6. Interesting question....

The 22nd Amendment only forbids being ELECTED President more than twice. If he ran for Veep, he wouldn't be elected President.

Not that any of this matters. He'll never do it, Hillary would never ask him, and it wouldn't be a good thing if he did, IMO.
</post>
<post id="p15" author="dumbcat" datetime="2015-04-08T14:10:00">
32. Bill Clinton would be eligible

For the Presidency in that case. Read what the Constitution says. "Elected to ..."
</post>
<post id="p16" author="cali" datetime="2015-04-08T14:20:00">
34. I doubt it, but as its never been adjudicated, it's hard to know.
</post>
<post id="p17" author="dumbcat" datetime="2015-04-08T15:47:00">
37. The language is pretty clear - "Elected"

means "elected", unless you are trying to argue against the clear terminology. And, of course, some will.
</post>
<post id="p18" author="cali" datetime="2015-04-08T16:04:00">
39. let me point you to the 12th amendment which is also clear as a bell and conflicts
</post>
<post id="p19" author="dumbcat" datetime="2015-04-08T16:09:00">
40. Conflicts with what?  nt

nt
</post>
<post id="p20" author="tularetom" datetime="2015-04-08T12:03:00">
3. And they could give the entire country away to Wall Street TWICE as fast!!1!

It wouldn't be just the GOP and RW going completely insane.

It would be the final blow to America's middle class.
</post>
<post id="p21" author="InAbLuEsTaTe" datetime="2015-04-08T12:22:00">
19. So true. Thankfully, Bill is ineligible to be Hillary's VP. Plus he'd overshadow her; Hillary wouldn't stand for that.
</post>
<post id="p22" author="hifiguy" datetime="2015-04-08T16:38:00">
41. ^THIS^

They already sold the Democratic party to the banksters and the MIC, why not finish the job by just giving them the entire country to use as their litterbox.
</post>
<post id="p23" author="Capt. Obvious" datetime="2015-04-08T12:08:00">
7. Uh, no. That's no more legal than a person born in Canada running for President.
</post>
<post id="p24" author="Adrahil" datetime="2015-04-08T12:09:00">
11. What?

A person born in Canada CAN be President, so long as they were born to a citizen. As long as you are BORN a citizen, you're a NBC.
</post>
<post id="p25" author="Aristus" datetime="2015-04-08T12:08:00">
8. Nope.

No one can take the office of VP who isn't also eligible to serve as President. That leaves Bill out, much as I would love a third term for him.
</post>
<post id="p26" author="djean111" datetime="2015-04-08T12:09:00">
10. I would not even walk out of my front door for that ticket.

Why not just get all this posturing over with and have a Hillary/Jamie Dimon ticket? Be more straight to the point, really.
</post>
<post id="p27" author="InAbLuEsTaTe" datetime="2015-04-08T12:24:00">
20. Hillary/Jeb more like it. Wouldn't shock me either. Ughhh
</post>
<post id="p28" author="William769" datetime="2015-04-08T12:09:00">
12. That is not going to happen.

I would not even entertain the idea.
</post>
<post id="p29" author="Raine1967" datetime="2015-04-08T12:31:00">
24. +1  Was going to post the same thing.

Not worth wasting the discussion on it.
</post>
<post id="p30" author="William769" datetime="2015-04-08T12:33:00">
25. GMTA!
</post>
<post id="p31" author="Raine1967" datetime="2015-04-08T12:34:00">
26. back atcha William!
</post>
<post id="p32" author="n2doc" datetime="2015-04-08T12:14:00">
15. And then if Bill became President he could appoint Obama as VP

Paging Alex Jones....
</post>
<post id="p33" author="InAbLuEsTaTe" datetime="2015-04-08T12:26:00">
21. More likely Chelsea as VP - you know that's coming, then Charlotte (have to keep the royals in power, dontcha know?).
</post>
<post id="p34" author="hifiguy" datetime="2015-04-08T16:39:00">
42. No more Bushes.  No more Clintons.

Ever. That is all.
</post>
<post id="p35" author="Stallion" datetime="2015-04-08T12:35:00">
27. Damn that Would Be So Much Fun!!! LET's DO IT!!!

nm
</post>
<post id="p36" author="jmowreader" datetime="2015-04-08T12:15:00">
17. They'd have to move to do it

The Constitution says the electors cast ballots for a president and VP, at least one of whom is from a different state than the elector is. Most folks translate that to mean the two politicians can't be from the same state. No, what it means is, if Mike Crapo and Raul Labrador were the Republican candidates they could not receive Idaho's four votes. In practical application it'll never be tested because no one wants to write off a whole state.

If Bill were to pull $125,000 out of the bank and buy a house in Bald Knob, AR, he could declare as an Arkansas resident but it still looks flaky to me; have we no bench?
</post>
<post id="p37" author="djean111" datetime="2015-04-08T12:30:00">
23. I think that proposing scenarios like this are more to get people to somehow tacitly or unconciously

accept or entertain the idea of Hillary as already being the presidential candidate.
</post>
<post id="p38" author="jwirr" datetime="2015-04-08T12:16:00">
18. Doesn't the law say that he cannot be elected to 3 consecutive terms? He can run again himself

if it is not consecutive.
</post>
<post id="p39" author="InAbLuEsTaTe" datetime="2015-04-08T12:27:00">
22. No.
</post>
<post id="p40" author="jwirr" datetime="2015-04-08T12:38:00">
29. Okay. I looked it up. Thank you.
</post>
<post id="p41" author="guillaumeb" datetime="2015-04-08T12:37:00">
28. Clinton/Clinton vs. Bush/Bush?

The mind boggles
</post>
<post id="p42" author="Xithras" datetime="2015-04-08T13:38:00">
31. "Technically" it's a grey area that would unquestionably go to the Supreme Court

People have played "what if" scenarios with the 22nd Amendment ever since it was passed in 1947. While both sides of the argument adamantly proclaim that they're right, the reality is that the law is vague and won't be clarified until the Supreme Court chimes in. That probably won't happen until somebody gives it a try.

Article II, Section 1 of the Constitution defines "eligibility" to be President. It sets age requirements, residency requirements and citizenship requirements.

The 22nd Amendment, by its wording, prohibits a person from being ELECTED to the office of President. It does not contain any reference to eligibility, and has no wording stating that a person is ineligible to hold the office after two terms. Its wording is specific in that it refers to being "elected".

the 12th Amendment states that nobody ineligible to serve as President can serve as Vice President.

The debate revolves around the word "ineligible". While theintentof the 22nd Amendment was clear, thewordingcreates a loophole in that it technically does not make a two term President "ineligible", but merely "unelectable". Generally, the camps in the argument fall into a camp that supports its "implied meaning" and intent, and another camp that is strictly reading the letter of the law itself.

While it's a fun topic to debate, we'll never see this sort of thing actually happen. Because it would unquestionably go to the Supreme Court, there's a 50/50 chance that the VP would be thrown out of office within days of the election. That would put the newly elected President into a nightmare scenario of having to select a new nominee for Vice President, and then having Congress approve it. If you think that getting federal judges, cabinet members, and Supreme Court justices approved is a nightmare, can you imagine what would happen today if Congress were allowed to vet and approve the Vice President? No party is going to risk that, no matter how well liked their former two-term President may be. It would take political gridlock to an entirely new level.
</post>
<post id="p43" author="zappaman" datetime="2015-04-08T14:19:00">
33. Damn that would make heads explode!

And explode at other sites besides here!
</post>
<post id="p44" author="Major Hogwash" datetime="2015-04-08T15:06:00">
35. I was waiting for someone to start this discussion!!!!!!!!

I had a barf bag sitting next to my computer desk!!!

You win the internet, MastersNemesis!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

Because, you are absolutely correct!!!!!!
</post>
<post id="p45" author="TheMastersNemesis" datetime="2015-04-08T18:37:00">
44. I Just Thought It Was Funny.  But Boy Would It Be A Hoot To Watch The GOP &amp; RW If It Were Possible
</post>
<post id="p46" author="Tierra_y_Libertad" datetime="2015-04-08T15:48:00">
38. Take out the Clinton part and it might be a good ticket.
</post>
<post id="p47" author="EL34x4" datetime="2015-04-08T17:28:00">
43. And while President Hillary Clinton lived in the White House...

Vice President Bill Clinton would reside at Number One Observatory Circle, the VP's home on the grounds of the United States Naval Observatory. For the next four to eight years, they would rarely appear together.

Bill may or may not approve of this arrangement.
</post>
<post id="p48" author="Glassunion" datetime="2015-04-08T19:15:00">
46. So is corporate offshoring to evade taxes

Don't make it a good idea.
</post>
</doc>
