<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="ENG_DF_000183_20150318_F0000009G">
<headline>
Obama blames the guy actually responsible for the birth of ISIS for giving birth to ISIS. BASTARD!
</headline>
<post id="p1" author="Miles Archer" datetime="2015-03-18T12:46:00">
<quote>
I'm LOVING the right-wing outrage over this.
Unintended consequences: Obama traces origin of ISIS to Bush-era Iraq invasion
Published time: March 17, 2015 04:17
Edited time: March 18, 2015 09:46
http://rt.com/usa/241325-obama-isis-iraq-bush/

President Barack Obama traced the origins of Islamic State militants back to the presidency of George W. Bush and the invasion of Iraq back in 2003, arguing that its growth was an unintended consequence of the war.
In an interview with Vice News, President Obama said the rise of Islamic State (IS, also known as ISIS/ISIL) can be directly linked to Americas excursion into Iraq under Bush.
Two things: One is, ISIL is a direct outgrowth of Al-Qaeda in Iraq that grew out of our invasion, Obama said in an interview with VICE News. Which is an example of unintended consequences. Which is why we should generally aim before we shoot. 
Obama stated that he is confident a coalition consisting of 60 nations will slowly push back ISIL out of Iraq, but added that the challenge of stopping extremism wont stop unless there is a political solution to the internal strife affecting so many countries in the Middle East.
</quote>
</post>
<post id="p2" author="TheCowsCameHome" datetime="2015-03-18T12:49:00">
1. Wow, look how long Cheney's right arm is - that is amazing.

n/t
</post>
<post id="p3" author="randome" datetime="2015-03-18T12:58:00">
9. No, that's his left...oh, I see.

A ton of bricks, a ton of feathers, it's still gonna hurt.
</post>
<post id="p4" author="C Moon" datetime="2015-03-18T13:24:00">
15. Cheney looks like a ventriloquist with a Bush dummy
</post>
<post id="p5" author="TheCowsCameHome" datetime="2015-03-18T16:12:00">
40. Yeah, the arm goes up W's butt and out his sleeve!

That's really sumpin'!
</post>
<post id="p6" author="alfredo" datetime="2015-03-18T22:53:00">
61. That's why you never see his back. The head stick and controls are exposed.
</post>
<post id="p7" author="NoJusticeNoPeace" datetime="2015-03-18T14:45:00">
26. CHeney came out today and said Obama worst president of all time

I want dickless to be shamed somehow, in a severe way
</post>
<post id="p8" author="lastlib" datetime="2015-03-18T20:46:00">
51. all that exercise raising it and shouting "Sieg Heil!" has had an effect.

pasty white skin results from spending so much time wearing sheets, suppose??
</post>
<post id="p9" author="ND-Dem" datetime="2015-03-18T21:01:00">
55. OK, what in cheney's background makes you think he's the puppeteer and bush is the

puppet?

The bush family's link to power goes way back, to the Civil war and railroad era.

Cheney's goes back to...cheney. Unless you know something I don't.
</post>
<post id="p10" author="kacekwl" datetime="2015-03-19T00:24:00">
63. Even the Bush

family knew W needed help moving his lips. Enter Cheney.
</post>
<post id="p11" author="ND-Dem" datetime="2015-03-19T02:39:00">
66. and you know the bush family's secret thoughts because....
</post>
<post id="p12" author="AlbertCat" datetime="2015-03-19T12:03:00">
72. and you know the bush family's secret thoughts because....

Because there are no secrets involved and we can see and hear and have a brain.

How 'bout you?
</post>
<post id="p13" author="ND-Dem" datetime="2015-03-19T12:11:00">
73. weak.  *you* think bush is dumb &amp; needs a minder, ergo cheney is in charge.  to you,

that means "we can see and hear and have a brain".

or maybe not. just your supposition.
</post>
<post id="p14" author="AlbertCat" datetime="2015-03-19T14:58:00">
74. Oh please.....

...... what are you even arguing about?

Like we're making scientific analyses instead of snarky jokes.

And having lived thru the Bush years, and having a memory, it was obvious Dubya was not that engaged with that whole governing thing (one page DPB's...he didn't even read, y'know). Not so good for press conferences and PR either but it's what they got. He, like Reagan was a PR President.... a GOP idea.

But

Yes yes, I cannot see into the Bush family collective brain. Nothing about decades of external behavior or incidences and verbiages could possibly give us a clue as to what they are like or how they operate. THANK YOU, ND-Dem, for being so fair and understanding. I grovel.... I grovel in mortification...
</post>
<post id="p15" author="ieoeja" datetime="2015-03-19T17:09:00">
79. You do know who picked Cheney to be W's VP, don't you? n/t
</post>
<post id="p16" author="TwilightGardener" datetime="2015-03-18T12:50:00">
2. There's no question how ISIS came about.  These are former

disgruntled Iraqi military officers (under Saddam) and AQ-aligned Sunnis who were too hard to kill the first time around. They went underground like cockroaches and then got the band back together a few years later. It's really that simple.
</post>
<post id="p17" author="meow2u3" datetime="2015-03-19T10:17:00">
70. You summed it up perfectly in sound bite form

Bravo!
</post>
<post id="p18" author="InAbLuEsTaTe" datetime="2015-03-19T16:35:00">
76. Yes and anyone stupid enough to support those aholes and vote for the IWR is disqualified to be President...

Can everyone at least agree on that?!
</post>
<post id="p19" author="cilla4progress" datetime="2015-03-18T12:51:00">
3. What this photo says to me:

heil
</post>
<post id="p20" author="Romeo.lima333" datetime="2015-03-18T12:52:00">
5. i wish it was saying "bye-bye we're off to the hague"
</post>
<post id="p21" author="Myrina" datetime="2015-03-18T13:43:00">
18. It says "Smile nice for the camera, Georgie, and you can have ice cream after your nap"

to me ...
</post>
<post id="p22" author="Thor_MN" datetime="2015-03-18T18:21:00">
43. Sprinkles are for winners.
</post>
<post id="p23" author="awoke_in_2003" datetime="2015-03-18T20:27:00">
49. Off topic...

but I love that commercial. "Flo" delivers that line so deadpan.

on edit: Added the video for those who haven't seen it. She makes him feel so good for 25 seconds, then buries the knife
</post>
<post id="p24" author="lastlib" datetime="2015-03-18T20:49:00">
52. Never put this creature on my screen again.

I am so sick of that ******* "Flo", I could retch when I see her mug.

(nuttin' personal, awoke!)
</post>
<post id="p25" author="awoke_in_2003" datetime="2015-03-18T20:50:00">
53. Ah, come on now....

I hear you, though
</post>
<post id="p26" author="Myrina" datetime="2015-03-18T22:34:00">
60. you're not alone ...

n/t
</post>
<post id="p27" author="Romeo.lima333" datetime="2015-03-18T12:52:00">
4. kr
</post>
<post id="p28" author="Fred Sanders" datetime="2015-03-18T12:53:00">
6. Populist President Obama is what we have in power, no need to wait for Warren. Get his back.
</post>
<post id="p29" author="rhett o rick" datetime="2015-03-18T16:36:00">
42. How exactly is he a "Populist President".  His stands on fracking, the TPP,

indefinite detention, the Patriot Act, torture, war crimes, drone killings, persecution of whistle-blowers and journalists, etc., preclude him from being a "Populist President". Sen Warren wants to control Wall Street, while Pres Obama and Holder are willing to give them a pass. Almost all of Pres Obama's appointees have been conservatives. How again is he "Populist"???
</post>
<post id="p30" author="Sheepshank" datetime="2015-03-18T12:54:00">
7. ahhh, so this is what prompted Cheney's little outburst

I figured it had something to do with questioning his lying, cheating, reign of terror.

What a petulant man-child
</post>
<post id="p31" author="sinkingfeeling" datetime="2015-03-18T12:57:00">
8. Too bad 99.5% of the population will never see nor read this.
</post>
<post id="p32" author="bulloney" datetime="2015-03-18T19:05:00">
45. Oh, they're reading it and, from what I've seen in the social media, people are furious at Obama.

How dare he not accept the blame for ISIS and blame Bush/Cheney on top of that!

When will these liberals (the fact these goofs call Obama a liberal is laughable) start owning up to their mistakes (another good laugh at their skills of projecting).

I've been reading it on FB and other social media for the past day.
</post>
<post id="p33" author="marym625" datetime="2015-03-18T13:04:00">
10. The easiest, best and most important thing to do

In letting the world and American citizens know that we realize how horrible what we did was, is to prosecute those that committed war crimes.
</post>
<post id="p34" author="snooper2" datetime="2015-03-18T13:06:00">
11. Shithole RT using a real news organizations work....

There should be some kind of international law against that LOL
</post>
<post id="p35" author="MisterP" datetime="2015-03-18T13:14:00">
12. Bush tried to keep us in, kept Gitmo open, and used ultra-Salafists to overthrow Libya and Syria?
</post>
<post id="p36" author="Cha" datetime="2015-03-18T19:46:00">
48. How sweet.. you're sticking up for bush.
</post>
<post id="p37" author="jillan" datetime="2015-03-18T13:15:00">
13. IF ONLY we had media that would actually report on this disturbing fact so the President

wouldn't have to. Now it becomes political when it an actual fact.

If only that librul media would do their job.
</post>
<post id="p38" author="Dont call me Shirley" datetime="2015-03-18T13:22:00">
14. Working on ensuring no bush will ever hold public office again, awesomeness.
</post>
<post id="p39" author="prayin4rain" datetime="2015-03-18T13:25:00">
16. YES!   n/t
</post>
<post id="p40" author="hollowdweller" datetime="2015-03-18T13:28:00">
17. If you want to go back further

Really the CIA in Afghanistan was who birthed the large multi national Islamic fighting force that first formed in Afghanistan, then moved to the former Yugoslavia, and finally wound up in Iraq and Syria. You could say we gave the seed money, and really our invasion of Iraq and then what went down in Syria gave it a huge shot in the arm.

I really only think that it can currently be defeated on an ideological basis and by not sending arms to the middle east, because the arms can be captured or sold to them from who we originally give them to. Another important part is to become energy independent. I think Obama actually knows this and is quietly trying to both do it and educate the public. However the GOP, and sadly, too many of our countrymen think that force is somehow an option that will work.

For years after Vietnam we understood this reality. However one bad thing I think about the Gulf War and our success there was that it sort of emboldened the hawks. After the self congratulatory wallowing we were doing after the Gulf War went so well, combined with the fall of the USSR I knew our imperialistic and hawkish elements were going to lead the country down the path of problems again.
</post>
<post id="p41" author="randr" datetime="2015-03-18T13:44:00">
19. The war in Kuwait was when Papa put the airfields on Saudi land

infuriating the dormant extremists, namely Bin Laden and ilk.
</post>
<post id="p42" author="napkinz" datetime="2015-03-18T14:06:00">
20. ...
</post>
<post id="p43" author="pansypoo53219" datetime="2015-03-18T14:18:00">
21. why in the hell is the gnewz telling us what stupid head cheeney thinks?
</post>
<post id="p44" author="riderinthestorm" datetime="2015-03-18T14:21:00">
22. Bzzzzzt! This is an RT article and therefore is simply Russian propaganda!

or something like that...

K&amp;R
</post>
<post id="p45" author="knightmaar" datetime="2015-03-18T14:23:00">
23. Educate them over there so we don't have to fight them over here.
</post>
<post id="p46" author="BainsBane" datetime="2015-03-18T14:27:00">
24. There is a lot of blame to go around

I found Frontline's program "The Rise of Isis" quite interesting.

http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/rise-of-isis/
</post>
<post id="p47" author="YOHABLO" datetime="2015-03-18T15:54:00">
38. It seemed a bit Hawkish to put U.S. troops on the ground. I don't want to see more young people

killed and or beheaded. We have to encourage the surrounding armies (Sauds etc) to take up the cause. If they want stability in the region then they'll have to step up. The Pentagon loves war as well as the MIC (Military Industrial Complex)
</post>
<post id="p48" author="BainsBane" datetime="2015-03-18T16:08:00">
39. I don't know what the solution is

and I don't want to see troops on the ground either. My point in posting the link was to show the blame goes beyond Bush. Obama played a role as well through neglect and ignoring Malaki's purges of the Sunni. The whole thing is a royal screw up, and now we are facing the consequences.
</post>
<post id="p49" author="Submariner" datetime="2015-03-18T14:43:00">
25. Let's give Obama a THIRD TERM as President

Have Pelosi and Reid introduce a Bill to bomb some place that republicans hate, like the MSNBC studio during the weekend so Rachel is safe, and then like the republicans, sneakily bury a sentence in the Bill that allows Obama to run for a third term. He's too good to let go so soon.

Let's do it!
</post>
<post id="p50" author="NoJusticeNoPeace" datetime="2015-03-18T14:48:00">
28. A great "I told you so" would be for Obama to be followed by a Walker or Cruz

The stark difference would make some people hang their heads in shame

We were shown this difference when Obama (superman in some respects) took over after W, the worst president of all time.

We saw how different it was and we forgot about it so quickly, some of us did, anyway.
</post>
<post id="p51" author="Half-Century Man" datetime="2015-03-18T15:11:00">
30. Uh...Bad idea.

Allowing an axe murderer in the house because your kids make a mess and talk back ....isn't a very good idea.
</post>
<post id="p52" author="Stellar" datetime="2015-03-18T14:58:00">
29. hear, hear!
</post>
<post id="p53" author="AikenYankee" datetime="2015-03-18T15:35:00">
34. I've been "threatening" by

conservative friends with a Third Obama term for six years now! Drives them crazy!!

Sounds like a great idea to me .... (except for that constitutional thing.)
</post>
<post id="p54" author="leveymg" datetime="2015-03-18T21:03:00">
57. Michelle.

Third and fourth Obama terms. Beats the alternatives.
</post>
<post id="p55" author="BlancheSplanchnik" datetime="2015-03-18T14:48:00">
27. kicking, rec, shared.   n/t
</post>
<post id="p56" author="AtomicKitten" datetime="2015-03-18T15:11:00">
31. Hillary blamed the rise of ISIS on Obama's "failure" to intervene in Syrian civil war.

http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2014/08/hillary-clinton-failure-to-help-syrian-rebels-led-to-the-rise-of-isis/375832/
</post>
<post id="p57" author="Chan790" datetime="2015-03-18T16:35:00">
41. ...and here I was...

thinking that I didn't need another reason to hate Hillary.
</post>
<post id="p58" author="AtomicKitten" datetime="2015-03-18T18:33:00">
44. There's plenty of material no doubt.

Obama could have left her dumb ass in the Senate where she chaired no committees and had no seniority. But he gave her actual foreign policy experience as SOS to bolster her resume that largely consisted of fantastical claims such as bringing peace to Ireland and ducking sniperfire in Tuzla. What does he get for his gracious generosity? She stabs him in the back and self-promotes her hawkish views. She forgets she lost in large part because of her hawkishness, so I look forward to a reckoning that is surely headed her way.
</post>
<post id="p59" author="leveymg" datetime="2015-03-18T21:34:00">
58. What is striking is that HRCs positions are Bibis and the Saudis

She makes that quite clear in her interview that the "maximalist" stance she takes on every issue from Israel's bombing of Gaza to Iran enrichment is essentially the same as Bibi's and the Saudis'.

As she admits, "there is no distance" on these matters - Hillary might as well be Bibi or the Saudi foreign minister.

Does no one else find this remarkable? Are we really expected to quietly accept her nomination as the Democratic candidate for President without even discussion?
</post>
<post id="p60" author="AtomicKitten" datetime="2015-03-19T01:17:00">
65. Yes, it is disturbing.

And ignored for the most part by too many here.

It is my #1 reason, and lord knows there are many, why I cannot and will not vote for her.
</post>
<post id="p61" author="leveymg" datetime="2015-03-19T08:05:00">
67. Thanks for the link to that HRC interview in The Atlantic.  Substantiates a lot ME specifics.

Hillary has been enabling the "maximalist" hard-line positions of the Israeli RW and the Saudis, and will by all indication continue to do so. Clinton, along with the GOP neocons, share responsible for much of the chaos and sectarian violence that is spilling over out of the region. That fact is widely ignored around here. Let's see what we can do about that.
</post>
<post id="p62" author="AtomicKitten" datetime="2015-03-20T02:42:00">
80. I'm in.

<quote>
Let's see what we can do about that.
</quote>

</post>
<post id="p63" author="red dog 1" datetime="2015-03-19T16:18:00">
75. Thanks for the link

God, I hope Bernie Sanders becomes a Democrat and runs against HRC for the Democratic nomination.
</post>
<post id="p64" author="InAbLuEsTaTe" datetime="2015-03-19T16:38:00">
77. Thanks AK for the reminder. With that idiocy and her IWR vote, Hillary succeeds only in embarrassing herself.
</post>
<post id="p65" author="obxhead" datetime="2015-03-18T15:11:00">
32. I think "unintended" is a real stretch.

I believe everything that happened was well planned and quite intentional.
</post>
<post id="p66" author="Tom Ripley" datetime="2015-03-18T15:37:00">
35. +1000
</post>
<post id="p67" author="mopinko" datetime="2015-03-18T21:01:00">
56. yup. what better way to keep the war machine in high gear

than to bomb a country that did nothing to deserve it.
we should have invaded saudi arabia if we were really trying to punish the perpetrators of 9/11.
</post>
<post id="p68" author="WDIM" datetime="2015-03-18T15:19:00">
33. Average age of ISIL recruit is between 16-21

These are the children of the Iraq war.

Would be interesting to know how many ISIL fighters are orphans or had family killed during the Iraq war.

This was my biggest argument against the Iraq war that it would lead to a generation of children growing up with hate and vengence in their heart thus leading to more terrorism and war.
</post>
<post id="p69" author="the_sly_pig" datetime="2015-03-18T15:49:00">
36. Chainee's ventriloquist act is something to see....

And with only one hand!!!
</post>
<post id="p70" author="Jefferson23" datetime="2015-03-18T15:53:00">
37. Excellent statements. K&amp;R
</post>
<post id="p71" author="Initech" datetime="2015-03-18T19:39:00">
46. Pass the butter. It will be fun watching their heads explode.
</post>
<post id="p72" author="Cha" datetime="2015-03-18T19:44:00">
47. The President warned them in Oct 2002 in his speech against invading Iraq.. did they listen? Are

you kidding!

Mahalo Miles
</post>
<post id="p73" author="ut oh" datetime="2015-03-18T20:40:00">
50. Is that Cheney's hand

up the back of W's shirt? The puppet master at work....
</post>
<post id="p74" author="former9thward" datetime="2015-03-18T20:55:00">
54. I thought we were told RT is a worthless source.

That should not even be allowed on DU. My, how time has changed.....
</post>
<post id="p75" author="Bluenorthwest" datetime="2015-03-18T22:05:00">
59. The interview is with Vice News, this story reports on that story. The OP used RT's reporting on

Vice News instead of just linking to the interview. Here's the source:
https://news.vice.com/video/president-obama-speaks-with-vice-news
</post>
<post id="p76" author="former9thward" datetime="2015-03-19T10:28:00">
71. Which is exactly what happened when many others have used RT.

But based on the subject matter they are slammed for using "Putin's propaganda". Here not so much....
</post>
<post id="p77" author="samsingh" datetime="2015-03-18T23:27:00">
62. i hate the picture of those two asswip..

pure evil
</post>
<post id="p78" author="Marr" datetime="2015-03-19T00:31:00">
64. Certainly not unforeseen. And it was only 'unintended' in the sense that

the greedy, arrogant assholes in charge didn't really give a shit about such side effects. They had their short term goals and lots of dick to waggle, and they just barged forward and did it with the the acquiescence of the political establishment and lots of media cover.
</post>
<post id="p79" author="L0oniX" datetime="2015-03-19T09:42:00">
68. Saddam was right.
</post>
<post id="p80" author="B Calm" datetime="2015-03-19T09:44:00">
69. Spot on! +1
</post>
<post id="p81" author="red dog 1" datetime="2015-03-19T16:44:00">
78. Islamic State owes it's very existence to the Project for the New American Century (PNAC)

"PNAC, co-founded by William Kristol and Robert Kagan, was a neo-conservative think tank (1997-2006) that had strong ties to the American Enterprise Institute.
PNAC is noteworthy for it's focus on Iraq, a preoccupation that began before Bush became president and predates the attacks of September 11, 2001."

More:
http://www.sourcewatch.org/index.php/Project_for_the_New_American_Century
</post>
</doc>
