<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<doc id="ENG_DF_000261_20150321_F00000081">
<headline>
Is there room for a non-Hillary Democratic candidate?
</headline>
<post id="p1" author="TheDemSocialist" datetime="2015-03-21T00:23:00">
While some Democrats might eye the White House for 2016, they may be leery of crossing Hillary Clinton. CNN's Jeff Zeleny reports.

Video @: Is there room for a non-Hillary Democratic candidate?

Will anyone else run? Yes. Who is it actually gonna be? That is a question that is pretty much up in the air right now. Hillary is pretty much a given, but there will be someone against her. Im putting my money on this: O'Malley and Sanders. Sanders is simply gonna run just to bring up the issues. He will bring up progressive issues, and even make liberals uncomfterable being an open socialist. Then there is O'Malley who will be the typical liberal Democrat who will actually realistically challenge her. If these two run, I will vote for Sanders in the primary, but if Clinton runs, I honestly dont know if I can vote for her. She is almost a spitting image of Bill. A centrist, free trade democrat. I may honestly cast my vote for a third party if "hill dog" runs.
</post>
<post id="p2" author="Paschendale" datetime="2015-03-21T02:04:00">
If nothing else, I would like a robust primary debate, as it could force Hillary a bit more to the left on some issues. Mainly, though, I just want a liberal in the white house the next time we need to pick supreme court judges.
</post>
<post id="p3" author="joG" datetime="2015-03-22T04:17:00">

<quote orig_author="Paschendale">
If nothing else, I would like a robust primary debate, as it could force Hillary a bit more to the left on some issues. Mainly, though, I just want a liberal in the white house the next time we need to pick supreme court judges.
</quote>

I was never understand, how people could have voted Nixon the first time and the second, when Watergate was already visible it was incredible. So why would anyone be able to elect Clinton with all that smell of corruption that clings to her? The thing about a politician most people can judge has nothing to do with economic or social policy. They do not have the informational analysis capabilities even if they have studied economics to make rational decisions. It is the chemistry of the person emotionally and rationally the question of trust. And to trust someone who has been involved in corruption is totally irresponsible.
</post>
<post id="p4" author="EMNofSeattle" datetime="2015-03-22T02:11:00">
I hope so, because there is no democratic contender I can get behind currently in field. Like previous elections I'll probably vote democrat for congress and state offices and republican for POTUS and US Senate. I can't stand Hillary, or her husband, I think they're effective politicians with staying power, but they're such despicable people I couldn't vote for them. I think Warren is a liar and not because of the Native American thing, but I don't buy she genuinely cares about the working class.

If I had to draft a president forcibly against their will id pick Ron Wyden of Oregon or even Bernie Sanders of Vermont, I hope my current congressman Derek Kilmer runs for prez in 2024 or so
</post>
<post id="p5" author="EMNofSeattle" datetime="2015-03-22T02:25:00">

<quote orig_author="joG">
&lt;b&gt;I was never understand, how people could have voted Nixon the first time and the second,&lt;/b&gt; when Watergate was already visible it was incredible. So why would anyone be able to elect Clinton with all that smell of corruption that clings to her? The thing about a politician most people can judge has nothing to do with economic or social policy. They do not have the informational analysis capabilities even if they have studied economics to make rational decisions. It is the chemistry of the person emotionally and rationally the question of trust. And to trust someone who has been involved in corruption is totally irresponsible.
</quote>

&lt;a onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Outgoing', 'en.m.wikipedia.org', '/wiki/George_McGovern']);" href="http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_McGovern" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;George McGovern - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;
</post>
<post id="p6" author="joG" datetime="2015-03-22T03:44:00">

<quote orig_author="EMNofSeattle">
&lt;a onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Outgoing', 'en.m.wikipedia.org', '/wiki/George_McGovern']);" href="http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_McGovern" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;George McGovern - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;
</quote>

Yep. McGovern was as bad as Obama. 

Which makes me wonder. ...?
</post>
<post id="p7" author="EMNofSeattle" datetime="2015-03-22T03:48:00">

<quote orig_author="joG">
Yep. McGovern was as bad as Obama. 

Which makes me wonder. ...?
</quote>

Not really, we can't say what kind a prez he'd be he didn't get a chance, he ran a terrible campaign after the Democratic Party got the rap for Vietnam
</post>
<post id="p8" author="fmw" datetime="2015-03-22T11:13:00">
"s there room for a non-Hillary Democratic candidate?"

If only there were room for an apolitical, non partisan candidate. Sigh.
</post>
<post id="p9" author="ttwtt78640" datetime="2015-03-22T11:27:00">
All that it took before was a community organizer that gave great teleprompter talks about the wonders of a huge nanny state. There is plenty of room, but one must have the gall (balls?) and money to challenge the Clinton machine.
</post>
</doc>
