<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130712.0047" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130712/20130712,2d4b0e389bf500542c2ab50d1875f230.xml">
<HEADLINE>
EGYPT CALLS FOR NEW LOOK AT MORSI PRISON ESCAPE
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: SUBS throughout to refocus on court case against Morsi; NEW headline.) ; (This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
CAIRO - Egypt’s new rulers gave new credence to a court case against the ousted president, Mohammed Morsi, and members of the Muslim Brotherhood on Thursday over their escape from prison during the uprising that toppled his predecessor, Hosni Mubarak.
</P>
<P>
The case was transferred from an appeals court to the State Security prosecutor for further investigation. No charges have been filed as yet. Its acceptance by powerful prosecutors follows the arrest of many Muslim Brotherhood members and is a new blow to the group by the military-backed government.
</P>
<P>
The detentions have been criticized by rights groups and the Obama administration, which spent Thursday walking back remarks made early in the day by a State Department spokeswoman, Jen Psaki, seeming to criticize Morsi as undemocratic and in so doing seeming to validate the military’s move to oust him.
</P>
<P>
At her regular State Department briefing Thursday, asked about the reactions, Psaki said she had been “referring to all of the voices that have been - we have heard coming - the millions, I should say, coming from Egypt, and how strongly they have voiced their views about his rule. But beyond that is up for the Egyptian people to determine.”
</P>
<P>
The renewed investigation of Morsi and members of the Muslim Brotherhood dates to the uprising that led to the ouster of Mubarak in 2011. Morsi and other Brotherhood leaders were arrested Jan. 28 and held in the Wadi Natroun prison north of Cairo, until they escaped two days later.
</P>
<P>
The case languished after Morsi was elected last year in the country’s first free presidential race, although local news outlets and Morsi’s opponents accused militants from Hamas, the Brotherhood’s Palestinian offshoot, of freeing their colleagues.
</P>
<P>
Morsi has not been seen publicly since his ouster July 3. It is unclear where he is being held, or whether he and the others will face the charges in court.
</P>
<P>
The ouster of Morsi and the subsequent suppression of the Brotherhood has enraged the group’s members and led to a spate of scapegoating attacks by Muslim extremists against Christians they accuse of supporting his fall, rights activists said.
</P>
<P>
While tensions between the Christian minority and extremist elements in the Muslim majority are not new, attacks have been reported across the country - in the northern Sinai Peninsula, in a resort town on the Mediterranean Coast, in Port Said along the Suez Canal and in isolated villages in upper Egypt.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>