<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130613.0153" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130613/20130613,9f711de6d1c51c33bdcced8ac7a86abe.xml">
<HEADLINE>
SOUTH AFRICAN LEADER CITES 'PROGRESS' IN MANDELA'S CONDITION
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: TWEAKS lede; CORRECTS time element in 3rd graf; SUBS 2 grafs starting “Government officials” and ADDS 4 grafs to end with quote from grandson and Mandela background.);
</P>
<P>
JOHANNESBURG - After four days in the hospital battling a lung infection, former President Nelson Mandela of South Africa “is responding better to treatment,” President Jacob Zuma told Parliament in Cape Town on Wednesday.
</P>
<P>
“We are very happy with the progress that he’s now making, following a difficult few days,” Zuma said.
</P>
<P>
It was the first report of an improvement in Mandela’s condition since he was admitted to a hospital in Pretoria early Saturday after suffering a recurrence of a persistent lung ailment, a legacy of the tuberculosis he contracted during the 27 years he was imprisoned for opposing apartheid. His health has been frail lately, and this hospitalization was his fourth in the last seven months.
</P>
<P>
Government officials in the last few days had been more downbeat, describing Mandela’s condition as “serious but stable” with no improvement.
</P>
<P>
Mandela, 94, is being treated in an intensive care unit, where close family members have been visiting him regularly. Among them are his daughters, his former wife Winnie Madikizela-Mandela and his grandson Mandla Mandela. His current wife, Graça Machel, canceled a speech in London to be by his side.
</P>
<P>
Mandla Mandela, who is a traditional leader in the Eastern Cape village where his grandfather was born, spoke to reporters outside Mandela’s home.
</P>
<P>
“My grandfather is the father of the nation,” he said. “He’s embraced by the global community, and we appreciate the support that we’ve received.”
</P>
<P>
As an underground leader of the banned African National Congress, Mandela was convicted of treason 49 years ago Wednesday. He was sentenced to life in prison, but was released in 1990 as the government, under intense international pressure, began negotiating with Mandela and the ANC.
</P>
<P>
Mandela was elected as South Africa’s first black president in 1994 and served one term. He retired from public life in 2004, and has not been seen in public since 2010, when South Africa hosted the World Cup.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>