<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131003.0269" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131003/20131003,f599c1eeb3bda40ce0b806bdb454b49e.xml">
<HEADLINE>
LEADER OF FAR-RIGHT PARTY IN GREECE IS JAILED
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
ATHENS, Greece - The leader of the extreme-right Golden Dawn party was returned to custody Thursday after appearing before a Greek magistrate on charges of setting up a criminal organization, part of the government’s crackdown on a party described by Greek and European authorities as neo-Nazi and violent.
</P>
<P>
The magistrate’s order to remand Nikos Michaloliakos, the first political party leader to face jail since Greece’s seven-year military dictatorship ended in 1974, came a day after three of his fellow lawmakers facing similar charges were released from custody and told not to leave the country, and a fourth was ordered held pending trial.
</P>
<P>
During more than six hours of testimony in an Athens courtroom, Michaloliakos condemned the murder last month of a 34-year-old hip-hop artist and anti-fascist, Pavlos Fyssas, by a self-professed supporter of Golden Dawn, and said he did not know whether members of the party were involved in violence, according to a court official. “I condemn the murder, like I condemn violence in general,” he was quoted as saying. “I am not a Nazi.”
</P>
<P>
Leaving court early Thursday, Michaloliakos was defiant. “Long live Golden Dawn! Victory!” he declared as his wife, Eleni Zaroulia, another Golden Dawn member of Parliament, cried, “You’re a diamond!” and his daughter, Ourania Michaloliakou, urged him, “Don’t buckle, don’t give in!”
</P>
<P>
Michaloliakos was transferred to the capital’s high-security Korydallos prison later in the day along with Yiannis Lagos, another Golden Dawn lawmaker. Giorgos Patelis, the head of the party’s chapter in Nikaia, near the spot where Fyssas was fatally stabbed, and an officer from the regional police precinct accused of supplying Golden Dawn with information were taken to two other jails in central Greece, state television reported.
</P>
<P>
According to the police, Lagos telephoned Michaloliakos half an hour after the killing of Fyssas on Sept. 18. The lawmaker has been tied to protection and prostitution rackets as well as blackmail and money laundering, according to secret service documents leaked to the Greek media this week.
</P>
<P>
Later Thursday, a sixth lawmaker, Christos Pappas, the party’s second in command, was also ordered returned to custody after testifying for at least six hours before a magistrate. He was to stay overnight at the Athens police headquarters before his transfer to prison. Arriving at the capital’s court complex, Pappas told reporters, “Golden Dawn will run in the next elections, whenever they may be.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>