<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131128.0177" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131128/20131128,d203b49ecd5de0476b37e5fea7492565.xml">
<HEADLINE>
ARIK EINSTEIN, BELOVED ISRAELI SINGER, DIES AT 74
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
JERUSALEM - Arik Einstein, an Israeli singer and songwriter whose blend of folk and rock helped shape a new Hebrew popular culture and whose ballads became modern Israeli anthems, died Tuesday in Tel Aviv. He was 74.
</P>
<P>
His death, of an aortic aneurysm, was announced by Gabriel Barbash, director of the Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, where Einstein was taken after collapsing at home.
</P>
<P>
“There will be nobody to sing for us anymore,” Barbash told reporters and fans who had gathered outside the hospital Tuesday night, setting the tone for a national outpouring of grief and nostalgia.
</P>
<P>
On Wednesday, an estimated crowd of 10,000 poured into Rabin Square, the Tel Aviv plaza named for Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin, where Einstein’s coffin lay in state. His rendition of a modern Israeli ballad, “Cry for You,” became one of the motifs of the period after Rabin’s assassination in 1995.
</P>
<P>
“His songs accompanied us at all the stations of our lives - in our loves and disappointments, our ups and downs,” Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said at a memorial ceremony in the square, adding that Einstein symbolized “the land of Israel that is beautiful, true and pure.”
</P>
<P>
Einstein, who began his recording career in the 1960s, released nearly 50 albums, sometimes in collaboration with other artists. While he largely retired from the stage several decades ago and was little known internationally, his popularity at home barely waned. Last year he was voted best Israeli singer of all time by readers of the popular newspaper Yediot Aharonot. Einstein helped forge an authentic Hebrew rock culture with popular songs like “Me and You” and “Fly, Baby Bird.”
</P>
<P>
“His sound was new,” Motti Regev, an Israeli sociologist specializing in popular music and culture, told Israel Radio on Wednesday. “Israeli music was mostly connected to military bands and ideological music. He sought how to connect to popular music in the world, to rock, and connect it to what was taking place in Israel.”
</P>
<P>
Einstein’s music, crossing generations and ethnic boundaries, was a comforting and unifying force in a diverse and often divided country, and the embodiment of an older, more genteel Israel that some say does not exist anymore. He was also known for his appearances in movies and comedy skits.
</P>
<P>
Arieh Einstein was born in Tel Aviv on Jan. 3, 1939, the only child of Yaakov and Devorah Einstein. His father was an actor. He became Israel’s high-jump champion as a boy and performed his military service as a member of an infantry brigade entertainment troupe.
</P>
<P>
He married Alona Shochet in 1963, and they had two daughters. The couple divorced, remarried and divorced again. She died in 2006. Einstein had two more children, a son and a daughter, with his second wife, Sima Eliyahu, an actress. She and his four children survive him.
</P>
<P>
Described by friends and acquaintances as modest and bashful, Einstein stopped performing for live audiences in the early 1980s after being seriously injured in a car accident. Although he continued recording, he largely retired from the public eye in recent years. But the newspaper Maariv announced this week that Einstein would begin writing a weekly column for its weekend supplement. He had put the final touches on his first - and last - column in the hours before he died.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>