<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130710.0155" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130710/20130710,8d159a07051d38aea5fd1f2c4a3fa284.xml">
<HEADLINE>
EXTRADITED COLOMBIAN TO FACE CHARGES OF DRUG TRAFFICKING
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
A Colombian who has been described by his country’s president as “the last of the great kingpins” was extradited to the United States from Colombia on Tuesday to face charges that he manufactured large quantities of cocaine that he then trafficked to the U.S. and elsewhere.
</P>
<P>
Daniel Barrera is to be arraigned Wednesday and Thursday in U.S. district courts in Manhattan and Brooklyn, where he faces separate indictments. After those prosecutions, he will be arraigned in Miami on additional charges, the authorities said.
</P>
<P>
Barrera, also known as El Loco, was arrested in September in Venezuela as a result of a complex operation that included Colombian and Venezuelan authorities, the CIA, the Drug Enforcement Administration and the British intelligence.
</P>
<P>
He was later sent to Colombia, and his extradition was announced by the U.S. attorneys in the three jurisdictions and other officials, including Raymond W. Kelly, the police commissioner of New York; and Michele M. Leonhart, the head of the DEA.
</P>
<P>
An indictment in Manhattan says that Barrera relied on two Colombian terrorist organizations to carry out his operations, buying raw cocaine paste from members of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, or FARC, and processing it in laboratories in areas controlled by another group, to which he paid fees.
</P>
<P>
Barrera’s organization produced upward of 400 tons of cocaine a year, “enriching itself and the two terrorist organizations it paid off,” said Preet Bharara, the U.S. attorney in Manhattan.
</P>
<P>
Loretta E. Lynch, the U.S. attorney in Brooklyn, said Barrera’s organization was “marked by its worldwide reach, ruthless criminality and staggering profits.”
</P>
<P>
Barrera is charged in Manhattan with one count of narcotics importation conspiracy, which carries a maximum sentence of life in prison. He faces a money laundering conspiracy charge in Brooklyn. His lawyer declined to comment.
</P>
<P>
Officials have said that Barrera, while residing in Venezuela, changed his appearance through plastic surgery, slept in different places and burned his fingertips to try to make it impossible to identify him.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>