<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20131220.0283" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20131220/20131220,e55769c57ae4303f02d74a87c5c09f1f.xml">
<HEADLINE>
NIGELLA LAWSON ASSISTANTS FOUND NOT GUILTY OF FRAUD
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
LONDON - Two Italians sisters who spent more than $1 million on celebrity chef Nigella Lawson’s credit cards were acquitted of fraud charges Friday by a London jury.
</P>
<P>
The sisters, Francesca, 35, and Elisabetta Grillo, 41, testified that Lawson had given them permission to spend as they liked on the household credit cards in exchange for keeping quiet about her cocaine use.
</P>
<P>
Lawson, 53, was compelled under oath to admit to using cocaine after now former husband, Charles Saatchi, 70, called her “Higella” in a private email that was revealed in court. He later said he regretted the email and never saw her using drugs, but she accused him of “intimate terrorism” and intense jealousy, and with trying to destroy her reputation.
</P>
<P>
The couple divorced in July after he was photographed squeezing her nose and gripping her by the throat at a London restaurant. That incident and the fraud case involving the private life of the celebrity chef provided much fodder for Britain’s tabloids.
</P>
<P>
Lawson denied abusing drugs, testifying that she first used cocaine while caring for her first husband, John Diamond, when he was terminally ill with cancer; he died in 2001.
</P>
<P>
After the verdict, Lawson said in a statement, “I did my civic duty, only to be maliciously vilified without the right to respond.”
</P>
<P>
Prosecutors told the court that over just four months in 2012, the sisters spent thousands of dollars in personal charges on household credit cards, including trips to New York, hotel stays and designer leather goods, as well as clothes from labels such as Louis Vuitton, Christian Dior and Vivienne Westwood.
</P>
<P>
Neither sister was in the courtroom to hear the verdict. Elisabetta Grillo apparently suffered a panic attack in court Thursday and collapsed three times Friday, once in the courthouse.
</P>
<P>
The Grillos were each charged with a single count of fraud. The sisters were described by one of their lawyers, Richard Cannon, as “naturally relieved” by the verdict.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>