<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130828.0147" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130828/20130828,971c3a5906496e0acc9e89664454abc7.xml">
<HEADLINE>
FORMER JPMORGAN EMPLOYEE SURRENDERS IN 'LONDON WHALE' CASE
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
EDS: SUBS throughout with new writing, NO PICKUP; SUBS headline; CHANGES order of byline.) ; (This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
Weeks after the U.S. government charged Javier Martin-Artajo, a former JPMorgan Chase employee, with hiding trading losses that ultimately reached more than $6 billion, he had his first day in court Tuesday as he surrendered to Spanish authorities and kicked off what could be a lengthy extradition process.
</P>
<P>
Martin-Artajo, a Spaniard who worked in the bank’s London office, was released soon after his surrender and arrest. He agreed to remain at the disposal of the Spanish judiciary, but it was unclear whether his passport was confiscated to prevent him from leaving the country, according to a person briefed on the matter.
</P>
<P>
The criminal charges stem from a risky bet at JPMorgan’s chief investment office in London, where Martin-Artajo worked. The bet involved so-called credit derivatives, which allow traders to bet on the perceived health of companies like American Airlines.
</P>
<P>
When the bet soured in the spring of 2012, prosecutors claim, Martin-Artajo and Julien Grout, a lower-ranking employee, deliberately overstated the value of their positions to hide hundreds of millions of dollars in losses. The two were charged with wire fraud, falsifying bank records and contributing to false regulatory filings. Prosecutors also charged them with conspiracy to commit those crimes.
</P>
<P>
The arrest in Spain, the latest development in an episode that left a rare stain on JPMorgan’s once-stellar reputation, underscores the challenge U.S. authorities face in their pursuit of the traders. After announcing charges this month against Martin-Artajo and Grout, federal prosecutors and the FBI in Manhattan have encountered logistical hurdles.
</P>
<P>
British police issued an arrest warrant for Martin-Artajo at the behest of authorities in New York, and then visited his house in London only to find that he was gone. According to his lawyers, Martin-Artajo left London “on a long-planned vacation” to his native Spain without knowing of the pending charges.
</P>
<P>
Grout, for his part, left London this year for his native France, which typically does not extradite its citizens. His lawyer, Edward Little, explained that his client also spent a brief period in the U.S., where his wife’s family lives.
</P>
<P>
According to a person close to the case, both of the former traders have indicated through their lawyers that they are open to extradition but only if prosecutors recommend bail.
</P>
<P>
Prosecutors have not charged a third trader, nicknamed “the London Whale.” That trader, Bruno Iksil, has reached a deal with the authorities in Manhattan that will spare him charges as long as he cooperates against his two former colleagues.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>