<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130619.0092" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130619/20130619,5bac92f8503f915b86b9f67f50635288.xml">
<HEADLINE>
MILITANTS ATTACK U.N. COMPOUND IN SOMALIA
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
MOGADISHU, Somalia - Militants staged a deadly assault on a U.N. compound here Wednesday, the latest in a series of attacks that have chipped away at the security gains the Somali capital has experienced in recent years.
</P>
<P>
The Shabab, the fearsome Islamist militant group that once controlled much of the capital, claimed responsibility for the attack, which government officials said left at least 15 people dead, including seven attackers.
</P>
<P>
The assault began when Shabab militants blew up a pickup truck rigged with explosives outside the compound, witnesses said. Militants armed with rifles and wearing explosive vests then stormed the facility on foot. Somali and African Union troops responded to the scene. The ensuing firefight lasted more than an hour, punctuated by a series of blasts.
</P>
<P>
Somalia’s minister of interior and national security, Abdikarim Hussein Guled, told reporters that the dead included four foreigners, four Somalis working for the United Nations as security personnel, as well as the attackers. In a statement, Somalia’s prime minister, Abdi Farah Shirdon Saaid, condemned “the senseless and despicable attack on innocent U.N. civilians.”
</P>
<P>
Mogadishu has experienced a period of relative calm since African Union forces and the Somali army pushed back the Shabab, leading it to announce a hasty retreat from the city in 2011. The militant group vowed to shift tactics more toward guerrilla assaults, assassinations and suicide bombings.
</P>
<P>
Militants “are now in complete control of the entire compound and the battle is still ongoing,” the Shabab said on its Twitter feed during the attack. “Inside the compound are several clueless foreigners who were lulled into a false sense of security by a strong disinformation campaign!”
</P>
<P>
The Shabab, who have sworn allegiance to al-Qaida, said that the group’s Martyrdom Brigade had carried out the attack.
</P>
<P>
The U.N. compound sits on a busy stretch of road near the airport. An ambulance worker, Abdirisak Moumin, said that he had collected 13 wounded civilians, six of whom died from their injuries.
</P>
<P>
Nicholas Kay, the U.N. special representative for Somalia, was outside the compound at a meeting nearby when the attack occurred. He called the attack an act of terrorism intended to derail Somalia’s drive toward recovery after decades of war and instability.
</P>
<P>
While the United Nations would review its security procedures, “the U.N. is committed to its mission,” Kay said in a telephone interview. “We’re here to help and we’re here to stay.”
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>