<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130625.0044" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130625/20130625,29784f391c76d2be664f6051f4501a5c.xml">
<HEADLINE>
VIGIL FOR MANDELA CONTINUES AS FAMILY MEMBERS HOLD EMERGENCY MEETING
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
This article is part of TIMES EXPRESS. It is a condensed version of a story that will appear in tomorrow’s New York Times.);
</P>
<P>
JOHANNESBURG - Singing crowds gathered outside the hospital where Nelson Mandela, South Africa’s former president, lay in a critical state for a third consecutive day Tuesday, as family members held an emergency meeting at his ancestral village.
</P>
<P>
Mandela’s eldest daughter, Makaziwe, at least two grandchildren and clan elders gathered at Mandela’s retirement house in Qunu, the remote southern village where he grew up, according to news media reports.
</P>
<P>
The subject of the meeting was not publicly disclosed, but Naplisi Mandela, an elder of the Mandela family, told the South African Press Association that they had gathered to discuss “delicate matters” - a euphemism widely interpreted to mean preparations for Mandela’s death.
</P>
<P>
Meanwhile, in Pretoria, doctors continued to treat Mandela for a lung ailment that he contracted on Robben Island, the notorious apartheid-era prison where he spent much of his 27 years behind bars until his release in 1990. He was hospitalized June 8, his fourth hospitalization since late last year.
</P>
<P>
In a statement, President Jacob Zuma said Mandela’s condition was unchanged. On Sunday, he visited Mandela and pronounced that his state had deteriorated from stable to critical.
</P>
<P>
Noting that Mandela’s 95th birthday is on July 18, Zuma urged South Africans to celebrate his achievements. Still, after 18 days of anxious vigil, many appeared to be steeling themselves for the worst.
</P>
<P>
Larger-than-usual crowds gathered at the gates of the Mediclinic Heart Hospital to pay tribute to Mandela, as people dropped off cards at a growing shrine and sang songs. “There is no one like you, Nelson Mandela,” one group sang in the Sotho language.
</P>
<P>
The emotional scenes were part of a perceptible shift in the national mood. Until recently, many South Africans had avoided talking about Mandela’s fate, calling it culturally inappropriate to speculate about any ailing figure, much less one as revered as Mandela, who played a central role in South Africa’s transition from white-led minority rule to historic multirace elections in 1994.
</P>
<P>
But now many are openly talking about the prospect of bidding him farewell.
</P>
<P>
Mandela’s declining condition came as President Barack Obama prepared to arrive in South Africa on Friday on the second leg of an African tour that will also take him to Tanzania and Senegal. But the South African government said a planned meeting between Obama and Mandela - both the first black leaders of their countries - now looked unlikely.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>