<DOC id="NYT_ENG_20130822.0136" type="story" from_file="/newswire/daily_process/nyt/english/source_data/20130822/20130822,7ce2c1d68e7423aacfe52c5251e63127.xml">
<HEADLINE>
A PINK-SLIP THANKS FOR A MAJOR DECISION
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
On Baseball);
</P>
<P>
When John Gaherin, the chief labor negotiator for Major League Baseball, arrived for a meeting with the chief of the players union and baseball’s arbitrator, he carried an envelope in the pocket of his suit jacket.
</P>
<P>
It was two days before Christmas 1975, not a time to be conducting serious business, but Gaherin and Marvin Miller, the executive director of the union, knew why Peter Seitz, the arbitrator, had summoned them. They knew that the subject of the meeting would be as serious a bit of business as baseball had ever experienced, and Gaherin went to the meeting prepared.
</P>
<P>
Seitz had informally telegraphed his decision in a grievance case, and now he would formally hand his written opinion to the two men. As soon as he did, Gaherin handed Seitz the envelope. “You’re fired,” it said in effect.
</P>
<P>
Such is the perilous life of impartial arbitrators in baseball and other professional sports. Either side - the league or the union - has the right to fire them. Like managers, they are hired to be fired.
</P>
<P>
“He told me he had expected as much,” Michael Seitz, Peter’s son, said in a recent telephone interview. “His feeling was there was no other way to decide the case, because the baseball owners had been stupid in assuming that when they didn’t have a player under contract, they still had a contractual hold on him.”
</P>
<P>
Fredric R. Horowitz, a 64-year-old lawyer from Santa Monica, Calif., is the latest to take a turn. He will arbitrate Alex Rodriguez’s appeal of his 211-game suspension.
</P>
<P>
While arbitrators pay for their decisions, which anger either the owners or the players, they don’t always receive credit for the significance of their decisions.
</P>
<P>
Seitz, for example, was responsible for creating free agency in baseball with his decision in the 1975 Andy Messersmith-Dave McNally grievance, but I believe, as Marvin Miller used to complain, that some reports in the news media, including in The New York Times, mistakenly credited other cases: Curt Flood’s 1970 lawsuit against baseball and Catfish Hunter’s 1974 grievance against Charlie Finley.
</P>
<P>
Flood’s suit challenged the game’s reserve clause, the rule that bound a player to his team until he was traded, sold or released. Hunter’s grievance contended that Finley, the Oakland Athletics’ owner, had breached his contract.
</P>
<P>
The Hunter case was exactly what the union argued, a breach-of-contract case. Finley had not paid the premium on Hunter’s annuity, as stipulated in his contract, Richard Moss, the union lawyer, said, and the pitcher should be a free agent as a result.
</P>
<P>
Seitz, in his first year as baseball’s arbitrator, agreed with Moss’ argument and declared Hunter a free agent.
</P>
<P>
A year later, when Seitz ruled in the Messersmith-McNally grievance, he did not cite the Hunter decision as a basis for this decision. As a breach-of-contract case, it affected no player but Hunter. No other player could gain free agency based on Seitz’s decision on Hunter.
</P>
<P>
“It didn’t change the mind of a single owner,” Miller said of the Hunter decision in one of the many conversations we had on the subject. "The owners’ position on free agency was the same after the Hunter case as it was before.''
</P>
<P>
Nor, Miller added, did the Flood case affect the owners’ thinking on the reserve clause and free agency. The reserve clause had forever been the tie that bound players to their teams, whether they liked it or not.
</P>
<P>
Flood did not like it, and when the St. Louis Cardinals traded him to Philadelphia, he opted to sue the commissioner rather than go to the Phillies, contending that he should have the right to play where he wanted. The suit went all the way to the U.S. Supreme Court, where Flood lost.
</P>
<P>
The owners always argued that elimination of the reserve clause would ruin baseball, Miller said, and Flood’s loss in the lawsuit emboldened them to maintain their position.
</P>
<P>
As heroic as Flood was in pursuing his lawsuit, it fell well short of having an effect. Its failure was one of the reasons the owners were so confident of winning the Messersmith-McNally grievance in court when they appealed Seitz’s decision, which said players could be free agents if they played the renewal year in their contract without signing a new contract.
</P>
<P>
What the owners failed to understand, in their inexperience in labor matters, was that judges rarely overruled an arbitrator’s decision, doing so only if an arbitrator’s authority had been exceeded.
</P>
<P>
The clubs and the commissioner have not done particularly well before arbitrators in instances where players have been suspended for conduct off the field. That history continued last year when Shyam Das overturned Ryan Braun’s 50-game suspension.
</P>
<P>
Das was fired after his Braun ruling.
</P>
<P>
Baseball would have preferred settling all of the doping cases stemming from the investigation into Biogenesis, an anti-aging clinic that is believed to have distributed banned substances to baseball players. The union also seemed eager to settle. But Rodriguez has appealed his 211-game suspension.
</P>
<P>
Given the volatility of the Rodriguez case, it would not be surprising if Horowitz’s first major case were his last.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>